const data = 
[
    {
        problem: "Steve can fuel his compact car with either regular or premium gas. If Steve uses regular gas his car gets 27 miles per gallon, but if he uses the more expensive higher-octane premium gas his car gets 30 miles per gallon. Regular gas is currently $2.70 per gallon. Let the answers below represent the amount by which premium gas costs more than regular gas per gallon. Which of these is the smallest difference in price for premium that still leaves regular gas a better value?",
        answer: "(E) 0.32"
    },
    {
        problem: "A circle with center at (0, 2) is tangent to the graph of y = x2 at two points. If the radius of the circle is written as √ab, what is a + b?",
        answer: "9"
    },
    {
        problem: "Isosceles 4ABC has sides AB = AC =√2 and BC = 1. The cosine of the angle A is a rational number ab where a and b have no common factors. What is a + b?",
        answer: "7"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let f(x) = log4x + 3x − 7. What is the number of integers that cannot be solutions to f(x) < 1?",
        answer: "14"
    },
    {
        problem: "Given that x is the largest solution of x + 1/x = 3, what is the value of x3 + 1/x3?",
        answer: "18"
    },
    {
        problem: "If 0.x = 0.xxxx . . ., what is the positive x value satisfying 10.x−11 + 10.x11 −11+ 10.x!= 1",
        answer: "9"
    },
    {
        problem: "Rectangle ABCD has width 6 and height 8. In the interior of the rectangle, two congruent circles O1 and O2 are externally tangent and O1 is tangent to AB and O2 is tangent to CD. Circle O3 is externally tangent to O1 and O2 and to AD and likewise Circle O4 is externally tangent to O1 and O2 and to BC. See the accompanying figure. The radius of circle O4 is a rational number a/b where a and b have noc ommon factors. What is a + b?",
        answer: "19"
    },
    {
        problem: "A rectangular cake 4 inches high and 12 inches by 24 inches is cut into separate congruent rectangular pieces by n−1 horizontal cuts and n−1 vertical cuts. If the total surface area (including the bottoms) of the small pieces is 2016 square inches more than the surface area (including the bottom) of the original cake, determine the value of n.",
        answer: "8"
    },
    {
        problem: "Suppose that the first term of an arithmetic sequence is an odd integer, and the common difference of the terms of the sequence is also an odd integer. Then which of the following is never true about the product P of three consecutive terms of the sequence?",
        answer: "(E) P is odd"
    },
    {
        problem: "A triangle MBG is inscribed in a regular octagon ABCDEFGH of side length 1 with vertex M of the triangle at the midpoint of DE, as shown in the figure. The area of the triangle can be expressed as a+b√cd wherethe prime factorization of c contains no squares, and gcd(a, b, d) = 1. What is a + b + c + d?",
        answer: "13"
    },
    {
        problem: "A 60◦sector ABC of a circle of radius 3 with center at A contains two semi-circles of radius 1 centered at D and E, where AD = AE = 2. The semi-circles are tangent to each other at F. See the accompanying figure. What is the area of the shaded region F BC bounded by the arcs F C, F B and BC?",
        answer: "(A) 5π6−√3"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let x and y be positive integers. If the average of 17, 36, 72, x2, and y2 is 150, determine the largest possible value for x.",
        answer: "24"
    },
    {
        problem: "For k a real number, compute the minimum possible value of the sum of the squares of the roots of x2 − kx + (k − 6) = 0.",
        answer: "11"
    },
    {
        problem: "ABCD is a rhombus. Points B and D lie on a parabola whose equation is f(x) = −√45x2 + k, C lies on the origin, E lies on the y-axis and is the trisection point of AB that is closer to A. The product of the coordinates of B can be written as mn where m and n are relatively prime positive integers. What is m + n?",
        answer: "7"
    },
    {
        problem: "If cos x + cos2 x = 0, what is the value of sin4 x − sin2 x?",
        answer: "0"
    },
    {
        problem: "Alice is passing a truck on the highway. The truck is traveling at a constant speed of 55 miles per hour and the truck is 52.8 feet long. Alice is passing at 60 miles per hour. How many seconds does it take Alice to pass the truck? (A mile is 5280 feet.)",
        answer: "7.2"
    },
    {
        problem: "Determine the product of all values of x such that the sum of x2− 2 and 4x2−1x is 0.",
        answer: "-8"
    },
    {
        problem: "If x is in radians, find the number of solutions in [0, 2π) tosin x cos x =1 − cos 2x2.",
        answer: "4"
    },
    {
        problem: "A number abc has three different non-zero digits. The sum of all 6 three-digit numbers formed with the same three digits in any order is 3108. What is the sum of the digits a + b + c?",
        answer: "14"
    },
    {
        problem: "Driveways in some Florida towns are composed of bricks in various patterns. Shown is one such pattern consisting of bricks 2 units by 1 unit. In terms of units, what is the square of the distance between points A and B where both are corner points of a brick?",
        answer: "194"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let f(x) = 9x2, A = (a, f(a)) for a > 0, and B = (a, 0). If the reflection of B across the line connecting A with the origin lies on the y-axis, what is 36a?",
        answer: "4"
    },
    {
        problem: "Triangle ABC is inscribed in a circle. The line ←→DE is tangent to the circle at B. The measure of ∠CAB is 50◦. What is the measure in degrees of ∠CBE?",
        answer: "50"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let b be a positive integer greater than 1. Determine all values of b such that there are exactly 306 two-digit numbers with a base of b.",
        answer: "18"
    },
    {
        problem: "There are 2 identical apricot colored cards, 2 identical blue cards, and 2 identical coral colored cards. In how many distinct ways can they be arranged in a row such that no two cards of the same color are adjacent?",
        answer: "30"
    },
    {
        problem: "Two fair six-sided dice, one is red and the other is green, are rolled. The sum of the spots showing on the top faces of the two dice is 6. What is the probability that the red die has 2 spots showing on the top face?",
        answer: "1/5"
    },
    {
        problem: "In 4ABC, AB = cos A and AC = 1. What is the maximum possible area of 4ABC?",
        answer: "1/4"
    },
    {
        problem: "A square of side-length 4 is the base of a regular pyramid with height 5. The circumscribing circle of the square is the base of a cone with the same vertex as the pyramid. See the accompanying figure. Thevolume of the space inside the cone but outside the pyramid can beexpressed as (aπ − b)/c where a, b, and c are positive integers withgcd(a, b, c) = 1. What is a + b + c?",
        answer: "123"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let x, y, and z be integers with 2 < x < y < z and let z be even. If x2 + y2 = z2 + 4, what is the least possible sum of x + y + z?",
        answer: "38"
    },
    {
        problem: "A number N consists of three non-zero digits. The sum of the other five three-digit numbers formed with the same three digits is 2017. What is N?",
        answer: "425"
    },
    {
        problem: "There are 780 families and each has a car, radio, and TV. There are 6 kinds of cars, 2 kinds of radios, and 5 kinds of TV available. What is the least possible number of families that could have the same kind of car, radio, and TV?",
        answer: "13"
    },
    {
        problem: "Simplify 3q√169 + √196.",
        answer: "3"
    },
    {
        problem: "The sum of three numbers in arithmetic progression is 39. Their product is 1560. What is the largest of the three numbers?",
        answer: "20"
    },
    {
        problem: "Shown below is part of an 8 by 8 table filled with numbers in the pattern indicated. Compute the sum of the numbers in the diagonal that runsfrom the top left to the bottom right. 2 -4 6 -8 10 -12 14 -1618 -20 22 -24 26 -28 30 -3234 -36 38 -40 . . . . . . . . . . . .............",
        answer: "-72"
    },
    {
        problem: "Note that the last three digits of 1 · 144 = 144 are 144. What is the least integer n greater than 1 such that n · 144 also ends in 144, i.e.n · 144 = . . . 144?",
        answer: "126"
    },
    {
        problem: "A sphere of diameter 12 sits in a hole which has the shape of the frustum of a cone. The sphere only touches the circular rim of the hole. The height of the top of the sphere above the top of the hole is 9, as shown in the diagram. What is the diameter of the wider base of the frustum of the cone?",
        answer: "(D) 6√3"
    },
    {
        problem: "Four friends Alice, Bob, Carol and Dave take turns rolling a single fair, six-sided die. Alice rolls first, then Bob, Carol and Dave in that order, continuing in order until someone rolls a “6” to win. What is the probability that Alice wins?",
        answer: "(B) 216671"
    },
    {
        problem: "The measured values of x and y are x = 3.5 ± 0.3 and y = 2.9 ± 0.3. Find the maximum possible value of |xy − 10.3|.",
        answer: "1.98"
    },
    {
        problem: "How many positive 3-digit numbers ABC are such that the product of the 2-digit numbers AB and BC equals ABC?",
        answer: "9"
    },
    {
        problem: "Astronauts are setting up a deep-space communication antenna on an asteroid. See the accompanying schematic figure. The asteroid is perfectly spherical with radius 100 kilometers. The astronauts erect 2 poles 500 meters tall perpendicular to the surface of the asteroid, located 10 km apart, measured along the surface of the asteroid. Between the poles is an antenna wire that is a circular arc concentric with the spherical asteroid. How much longer in meters is the antenna wire than the ground distance between the poles?",
        answer: "50"
    },
    {
        problem: "How many positive 6-digit palindromes are divisible by 11?",
        answer: "900"
    },
    {
        problem: "The circumference of a bicycle wheel is 220 cm. On a long bicycle ride of 55 km, what is the number of revolutions the wheel makes?",
        answer: "(B) 25000"
    },
    {
        problem: "Find the least positive value of y = 7 csc x - 3.",
        answer: "(B) 1:1"
    },
    {
        problem: "How many pairs of prime numbers are there with a sum of 40?",
        answer: "3"
    },
    {
        problem: "In a dice game played with two fair six-sided dice, a player first rolls both dice. The die with the higher count is set aside and the other die is rolled again. (If both dice show the same count, one is still set aside and the other rolled again.) The sum of the counts showing after the second roll is the score. The probability of getting 11 or better can be written as a b where a and b have no common factors. What is the sum a + b?",
        answer: "13"
    },
    {
        problem: "ABCD is a rectangle whose width is a and whose length is b with 2a < b and a and b integers. Points E and F are chosen on AB such that AE = FB = a. If the area of DEFC equals 18, determine the largest possible perimeter of ABCD.",
        answer: "40"
    },
    {
        problem: "Consider two concentric spheres. A plane intersects both spheres, the intersection being two concentric circles. If the area between the two circles is 36, what is the positive difference in the surface areas of the two spheres?",
        answer: "144"
    },
    {
        problem: "A hemisphere of radius 3 is concentric with a hemisphere of radius 9 and the flat surface of the small hemisphere Is glued to the flat surface of the larger hemisphere. See the accompanying figure. The surface area of the resulting solid can be written as air where a is an integer. What is a?",
        answer: "252"
    },
    {
        problem: "Alice is passing a truck on the highway. The truck is traveling at a constant speed of 55 miles per hour and the truck is 52.8 feet long. Alice is passing at 60 miles per hour. How many seconds does it take Alice to pass the truck? (A mile is 5280 feet.)",
        answer: "7.2"
    },
    {
        problem: "Determine the product of all values of x such that the sum of x2 − 2 and 4 x2 - 1 x is 0.",
        answer: "-8"
    },
    {
        problem: "If x is in radians, find the number of solutions in [0, 2π) to sin x cos x = 1−cos2x 2",
        answer: "4"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let f(x) = 9x2, A = (a,f(a)) for a > 0, and B = (a,0). If the reflection of B across the line connecting A with the origin lies on the y-axis, what is 36a?",
        answer: "4"
    },
    {
        problem: "How many positive 5-digit palindromes are there?",
        answer: "900"
    },
    {
        problem: "The winner of a triathlon race swam the first part of the race in 23 minutes, 31 seconds, then changed to the bike race in 47 seconds. The winner biked the second part of the race in 1 hour 17 minutes, and 22 seconds, then changed to the running race in 37 seconds. Finally, the winner completed the running race in 40 minutes, 9 seconds. What was the winners total time in hours, minutes and seconds?",
        answer: "(B) 2 hours, 22 minutes, 26 seconds"
    },
    {
        problem: "Some number of pirates are seated at a large circular table. They pass a bag containing 432 gold coins around the table, always in the same direction. Each pirate receives the bag, takes 3 coins and then passes the bag to the next pirate. The captain, who is included in the number of pirates, takes the first 3 coins and the last 3 coins. What is a possible number of pirates at the table?",
        answer: "11"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let r1 = 1 3 and let rn = 2 − 1 rn-1 for n ≥ 2. The value of r2017 in simplest form can be represented by m n. What is the sum m + n?",
        answer: "8060"
    },
    {
        problem: "A certain number of segments of length 1 are arranged as shown below. If the segments are separated and rearranged into 1 by 1 squares, what is the maximum possible sum of the areas of the 1 by 1 squares?",
        answer: "10"
    },
    {
        problem: "In △ABC, m∠A = 30◦, AB ∈ {1,2,3}, and AC ∈ {1,2,3,4}. The average area of all the triangles that can be formed using those sides can be written, in simplest form, as m/n. Note: Consider, for example, the triangle formed with AB = 1 and AC = 2 to be distinct from the triangle formed by AB = 2 and AC = 1 since the named sides have different lengths. What m + n?",
        answer: "9"
    },
    {
        problem: "The numbers 1, 1, 1, 2, 2, 2, 3, 3, and 3 are to be placed, one per cell, in the 9 cells of the 3 by 3 square shown below. Let E be the event that in each row and in each column there is exactly one 1, one 2, and one 3. If the 9 numbers are placed into the square at random, what is the probability of E occurring?",
        answer: "1/140"
    },
    {
        problem: "In △ABC, D lies on BC such that BD = 3 2CD. If AB = 2AC and AD = 3 2 CD, what is the value of cos ∠ADC?",
        answer: "17/33"
    },
    {
        problem: "A sphere of radius 2 sits at the bottom of a cylinder, and a second sphere of radius 4 rests on the first sphere inside the cylinder. The height of the top of the second sphere above the base of the cylinder is 9, as in the figure. The diameter of the cylinder can be written in simplest terms as a + b√c where the prime factorization of c contains no squares. What is a+b+c?",
        answer: "12"
    },
    {
        problem: "For any positive integer j, what is the greatest common divisor of 2j+1 and 2j + 5?",
        answer: "(A) 1"
    },
    {
        problem: "If each of the variables x, y, and z can take on the values 0 or 1 only, how many solutions does the equation have? x2 + y2 + z2 + 2xyz = 1",
        answer: "3"
    },
    {
        problem: "In equilateral △ABC with side length 1, the semi-circle RST is in- scribed with the endpoints R and S of the diameter RS on sides AC and BC respectively, RS parallel to AB and point T of the semi-circle tangent to side AB, as shown in the figure. What is the radius of the semi-circle?",
        answer: "(A) 3−√3 4"
    },
    {
        problem: "If a, b and c are positive integers such that (a, b, c) is the only ordered triple with 6a + 9b + 20c = 61, then what is a + b + c?",
        answer: "5"
    },
    {
        problem: "A fair coin is flipped and if it comes up heads, a red marble is placed in an empty urn, and if the coin comes up tails, a green marble is put in the empty urn. A second marble, green, is added to the urn already containing one marble. A marble is drawn at random from the urn, and it is green. What is the probability that the remaining marble is also green?",
        answer: "(D) 2/3"
    },
    {
        problem: "What is the maximum value taken on by the function f(x) = (1 4) x2−6x+3?",
        answer: "4096"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let P(x) be a polynomial of degree 3 such that P(k) = k2 k+1 for k = 1, 2, 3, 4. The value of P (5) can be written as a rational number abwhere a and b have no common factors. Find a + b.",
        answer: "77"
    },
    {
        problem: "Find the sum of all two-digit positive integers that are 10 times the sum of their digits.",
        answer: "450"
    },
    {
        problem: "A cube whose edge-length is 64 cm weighs 512 pounds. If there are 32 congruent smaller cubes with the same density as the large cube, the sum of whose weights equals the weight of the large cube, then the edge-length of any one of those cubes can be written in simplest form as a√3 b. (Simplest form means there are no factors of b which are perfect cubes.) What is a + b?",
        answer: "18"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let A and B be distinct digits with A = ̸= 0. A bag contains all four-digit numbers of the form ABAB. One is chosen at random. The probability mthat it is divisible by 4 can be written in simplest form as n . What is the value of m + n?",
        answer: "101"
    },
    {
        problem: "Given the system x + y1 = 4 x1 + y = 8 what is the ratio of y to x?",
        answer: "2"
    },
    {
        problem: "If f(x) = ax2 + bx + candf(−3) = 10 and f(3)=−8, then what is b?",
        answer: "-3"
    },
    {
        problem: "A line passes through (5, 2) and (6, 8). A parallel line passes through the point (5, 5). The coordinate where the line meets the x-axis can be written in simplest form as a/b. What is a + b?",
        answer: "31"
    },
    {
        problem: "Suppose you roll three fair six-sided red dice, and one fair six-sided green die. The probability that the number on the green die matches the least number showing among the three red dice is a/b in lowest terms. What is a + b?",
        answer: "7"
    },
    {
        problem: "What is the smallest positive number N such that when N is divided by each of 2/3, 4/7, and 5/4, the result is an integer?",
        answer: "20"
    },
    {
        problem: "Isosceles △ABC has sides AB=AC=5 and BC=6. The line through A parallel to BC intersects the line through B parallel to AC at C′. The line through B parallel to AC intersects the line through C parallel to AB at A′ The line through C parallel to AB intersects the line through A parallel to BC at B′. What is the area of △A′B′C′?",
        answer: "48"
    },
    {
        problem: "What is the sum of all 4-digit integers that can be made from the digits 2, 4, 6, 8 if each digit can be used only once in making a particular 4-digit number?",
        answer: "133320"
    },
    {
        problem: "A circle whose center is at B(0, 20) is tangent to the lines y = 2x and y = −2x. What is the x-value of the point of tangency in the first quadrant?",
        answer: "8"
    },
    {
        problem: "What is the maximum value for y among all solutions to the following system of equations? 5x − 2y = −4 x − 1 5 = 3 5y.",
        answer: "3"
    },
    {
        problem: "The set of all real values of k such that each of the following three equations has two different real solutions can be written as k < A. What is the value of A? kx2 + 4x + 4 = 0, x2 + 4kx + 4 = 0, x2 + 4x + 4k = 0",
        answer: "-1"
    },
    {
        problem: "If 0.375 = 0.14b where b is the base, what is the positive value for b?",
        answer: "5"
    },
    {
        problem: "Given △ABC with AB = 6, AC = 10 and AD = 6 where D is the midpoint of BC, the area of △ABC can be written as a√b where the prime factorization of b has no squares. What is the sum a + b?",
        answer: "22"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let x be an integer such that −500 ≤ x ≤ 500. Determine the number of values of x such that the values of 5 + x 3 + x lie no further from 1 than 0.01.",
        answer: "602"
    },
    {
        problem: "In △ABC, BD=DC, BA⊥CA, AD⊥BF, AE = 4 and BE = 8. The value of sin(∠FBC) can be written in simplest terms as a b. What does the product ab equal?",
        answer: "15"
    },
    {
        problem: "A circle CP with center P has radius 1 and another circle CQ with center Q has radius 2. The distance from P to Q is 5. The tangents to CP from Q intersect CQ at A and B. The tangents to CQ from P intersect CP at C and D. What is the ratio AB/CD of the lengths of the segments AB and CD?",
        answer: "(C) 1"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let ⌊x⌋ represent the greatest integer less than or equal to x. Thus, ⌊3.7⌋ = 3. For positive x and y, what is the sum of the areas of the regions in the coordinate plane of the solution set to ⌊x⌋ · ⌊y⌋ = 8?",
        answer: "4"
    },
    {
        problem: "At a convention for military people, four soldiers, a captain and a general pose in a line for a picture. In the photo, the general should always be to the right, but not necessarily the immediate right, of the captain. How many arrangements of people are possible for the photo?",
        answer: "360"
    },
    {
        problem: "Representing the base-10 fraction 15 as an expansion in base-2, the result is an infinite repeating binary number of the form 0.a1a2 ...aka1a2 ...aka1a2 ··· = 0.a1a2 ...ak. where each ai is either 0 or 1, and the length of the repeating block is k. What a1 +a2 +···+ak +k, that is, what is the number of the non-zero bits in the block plus the length of the block?",
        answer: "6"
    },
    {
        problem: "The complex number z is a solution of the equation z2 − z + 1 = 0 What is the value of z2017 + 1 z2017",
        answer: "1"
    },
    {
        problem: "Compute the area of the region bounded by |x|+y ≤ 4 and |x|+2y ≥ 2.",
        answer: "18"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let A be an appropriately large positive integer and bases b, c, and d be integers greater than 1. If AAd AAc = AAb and d ≤ 100, what is the largest possible value of the sum b + c?",
        answer: "34"
    },
    {
        problem: "For x in radians with 0 ≤ x ≤ 2018π, how many solutions are there to sinx = sin2x?",
        answer: "4037"
    },
    {
        problem: "For angles A and B in degrees, if cosAsinB = 1, compute sinAcosB.",
        answer: "0"
    },
    {
        problem: "If a, b and c are real numbers that make the following equality (n+2)2 = a(n−1)2 +bn2 +c(n+1)2 true for all integers n, what is a2 + b2 + c2?",
        answer: "19"
    },
    {
        problem: "How many solutions are there to the equation x2 2 = ⌊x⌋,where ⌊x⌋ is the floor function, the greatest integer less than or equal to x?",
        answer: "3"
    },
    {
        problem: "Six teams are invited for a state high school basketball tournament, and the first round will feature three games played simultaneously on three courts, pairing the teams at random. Three of the teams are from Circleton, the remaining 3 teams are each from different cities. The probability that two teams from Circleton will not be paired against aeach other in the first round can be written in lowest terms as b . What is a + b?",
        answer: "7"
    },
    {
        problem: "Triangle ABC has a right angle at B and BC > AB. Points D and E are located on AC and BC so that AB = BD = DE = EC. What is the angle measure in degrees of ∠BDE?",
        answer: "90"
    },
    {
        problem: "What is the positive difference of the solutions to the equation 15 √x = 8 − √x",
        answer: "16"
    },
    {
        problem: "What is the least integer N such that the decimal expansion of N! ends in exactly 10 zeros?",
        answer: "45"
    },
    {
        problem: "If the letters in NOONTOON are randomly arranged in a row, the probability that the three N’s are adjacent is, in simplest terms, a b. What is a+b?",
        answer: "31"
    },
    {
        problem: "What is the ordered triple solution (x, y, z) in integers to the following system? x + xyz = 87 y + xyz = 88 z + xyz = 91 Express you answer in the form abc.",
        answer: "347"
    },
    {
        problem: "What is the least value of p such that the expression −x2−px+p is non-positive for all x?",
        answer: "-4"
    },
    {
        problem: "Three circles, each of radius 1, are externally tangent, each to the other two as shown in the figure. A triangle with each side externally tangent to exactly one circle surrounds the three circles, as shown in the figure. The area of the triangle can be expressed as a√b + c where the prime factorization of b contains no squares. What is a + b + c?",
        answer: "22"
    },
    {
        problem: "How many distinct ordered pairs of integers (m, n) are there for which (a) m and n are from the set {−5,−4,...,4,5}, (b) |m−n|≤2,(c) m can equal n.",
        answer: "49"
    },
    {
        problem: "The coefficients of x2 − 22x + 111 = 0 are all written in base 4. Written in base 4 what is the largest real solution to the equation?",
        answer: "13"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let the set S contain all complex numbers such that z2 = z where z is the complex conjugate of z, i.e. if z = a+bi, then z = a−bi. How many elements does S contain?",
        answer: "4"
    },
    {
        problem: "Points A and B are situated on a solid cube of side 8 as shown in the figure. An ant starting at A wishes to get to point B as quickly as possible. The length of the shortest path from A to B on the surface of the cube can be written in simplest form as √k. What is k?",
        answer: "194"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let f(x) = mx + k where both m and k are positive integers. If f and f−1 intersect at a point where x = −5, what is the largest possible value of k such that m is less than 100?",
        answer: "490"
    },
    {
        problem: "Which of the following functions is strictly less than the function f(x) = √1 9 + (x-1)2 for all x?",
        answer: "(A) fA(x) = |x − 1|"
    },
    {
        problem: "Consider a right pyramid with square base of length s and height h. The ratio of the height to the base which makes the total area of the 4 triangular faces equal to 4 times the area of the base can be written in simplest terms as √a b where the prime factorization of a contains no squares. What is a + b?",
        answer: "17"
    },
    {
        problem: "A right pyramid has a regular √hexagonal base with side length 2. The height of the pyramid is h = 22. What is the total surface area of the 6 triangular faces? (The total surface area of the triangular faces is also called the lateral surface area.)",
        answer: "30"
    },
    {
        problem: "At Euclid High School, 30% of the students take geometry and the reminder take algebra. Of all the geometry students, 80% are boys. At Euclid High School, the number of girls is equal to the number of boys. What percentage of the boys take algebra?",
        answer: "52"
    },
    {
        problem: "From 3:15 PM to 5:00 PM, Tim was able to paint 91 boards. What is Tim’s average painting rate in boards per hour?",
        answer: "52"
    },
    {
        problem: "The fifth term of an arithmetic sequence is 16 and the ninth term is 32. What is the third term?",
        answer: "8"
    },
    {
        problem: "Equilateral △ABC has side AB in common with square ABDE and △ABC lies outside the square. What is the measure in degrees of ∠DEC?",
        answer: "75"
    },
    {
        problem: "The surface area of a given cube is K. If the cube is broken into 1000 congruent cubes, the sum of the surface areas of all those little cubes is M. Find M K.",
        answer: "10"
    },
    {
        problem: "For positive integers a and b, if ab = 1296, determine the minimum possible sum of a and b.",
        answer: "72"
    },
    {
        problem: "What is the least positive integer value of n such that |3x − 2| < n has 10 integer solutions?",
        answer: "15"
    },
    {
        problem: "If xy = 2, then what is x5y − 5?",
        answer: "27"
    },
    {
        problem: "A, B, C, and D are digits which are all less than 9 and are not necessarily distinct. What is the sum of all the elements of all ordered 4-tuples (A, B, C, D) such that √.AB = 0.CD where 0.AB represents the repeating decimal 0.ABABAB . . . and similarly for 0.CD.",
        answer: "28"
    },
    {
        problem: "If f(x) = 1 − 2x2, determine f(f(. . . f(1/√2))) where f appears 2019 times.",
        answer: "-1"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let the inner radius of a toilet paper roll be r and let the outer radius be R. If the volume of paper of the roll is equal to the lateral surface area (cylindrical sides only, not top and bottom) and R r = 2019, the length of the inner radius can be written in simplest form as a b. What is a + b?",
        answer: "1010"
    },
    {
        problem: "Circles P and Q are externally tangent at T, the radius of P is 12 and the radius of Q is 2. PTQ extended intersects Q at B. A lies on circle P such that AP ⊥ PB. R lies on AB such that RT ⊥ PB, and S is the intersection of circle Q and AB. The length of RS can be written in simplest form as m n. What is m+n?",
        answer: "14"
    },
    {
        problem: "What is the the rightmost digit of 20192019?",
        answer: "9"
    },
    {
        problem: "If the 6th-degree polynomial p(x) = (x + 1)(x − 1)(x + 3)(x − 3)(x + 5)(x − 5) is fully expanded, what is the sum of the coefficients?",
        answer: "0"
    },
    {
        problem: "If x3 + y3 = 84 and y2 + xy = 7, then what is x2 y − x + y?",
        answer: "12"
    },
    {
        problem: "A sequence fn has f1 = 0, f2 = 2019 and fn = fn−1 − fn−2 for n ≥ 3. What is f2019?",
        answer: "2019"
    },
    {
        problem: "Consider the following system of equations in x and y: √y−x2 = y−1 √x−y2 = x−1. What is the sum x + y over all ordered pair solutions (over the real numbers) of this system?",
        answer: "2"
    },
    {
        problem: "You plan to drive 500 miles at 65 miles per hour, stopping twice for 15 minutes each time to buy gas. You want to know the number of hours t the journey is going to take. Which of the following equations would you use to determine that number?",
        answer: "(B) 65 · (t − 1/2) = 500"
    },
    {
        problem: "Suppose a is negative and b and x are positive in the following expression a x + b What is the effect of increasing x on the value of the expression?",
        answer: "(A) Increases the value of the expression."
    },
    {
        problem: "Given isosceles △ABC with sides AB = BC = 25 and AC = 30, what is the side length of the largest square DEFG which can be inscribed in △ABC with G on AB, F on BC and D and E on AC?",
        answer: "12"
    },
    {
        problem: "Find the positive solution of the equation x2 + x − (2+4+6+···+2016) = 0.",
        answer: "1008"
    },
    {
        problem: "A semi-circle in inscribed in an equilateral triangle with side length 1. The diameter of the semi-circle lies on one side of the triangle. What is the radius of the semi-circle?",
        answer: "(A) √3 4"
    },
    {
        problem: "The sum 1 √1+√2 + 1 √2+√3 + ··· + 1 √9+√10 can be simplified to the form a+b√c where a, b and c are integers, and c has no factors which are the square of a prime number. What is the value of a+b+c?",
        answer: "1"
    },
    {
        problem: "One morning, Ann left home and cycled north at a steady speed. An hour later, Ann’s mother realized Ann had left without her lunch, so Mother set out at a steady speed of 10 miles per hour and cycled north after Ann, gave her the lunch and immediately turned around and again cycling at 10 miles per hour returned home exactly 3 hours after she started. What was Ann’s speed in miles per hour?",
        answer: "6"
    },
    {
        problem: "The increasing sequence 2, 3, 5, 6, 7, 8, 10, 11, 12, . . . consists of the positive integers in order with the perfect squares removed. What is the 200th number in this sequence?",
        answer: "214"
    },
    {
        problem: "The figure shows a irregular pentagon with vertices A, B, C, D, and E. The measures of the angles at B and E are each 90◦, as indicated in the interior of the pentagon. The measure of the angle at C is 105◦, as indicated in the interior of the pentagon, and 2∠A + ∠D = 360◦. What is the angle measure of A in degrees?",
        answer: "105"
    },
    {
        problem: "What is the sum of all of the coordinates of all points that have integer coordinates and that are solutions to x2 + y2 − 6x + 4y = −12?",
        answer: "4"
    },
    {
        problem: "On square ABCD, point E divides AB in the ratio AE : EB = 2 : 1 and point F divides CD in the ratio CF : FD = 1 : 1. Segments AF and DE intersect at G. The ratio of the area of △DFG to the area of square ABCD is a/b where a and b have no common factors. What is a+b?",
        answer: "31"
    },
    {
        problem: "If log3x 3 − 5 4 log9x 3 = 0, what is the value of x?",
        answer: "27"
    },
    {
        problem: "Suppose that G1 = 1, G2 = 1, and Gn = Gn−1 + iGn−2, where i = √-1 is the imaginary constant. What is the coefficient b of the imaginary part of G10 = a+bi?",
        answer: "-12"
    },
    {
        problem: "A set of 11 boxes is numbered consecutively from 1 to 11 and a set of 11 cards is numbered consecutively from 1 to 11. In how many ways can all the cards be placed in the boxes, one card per box, such that the sum of the number of any given box and the number of the card in that box is divisible by 3?",
        answer: "3456"
    },
    {
        problem: "What is the coefficient of the x5 term in the expansion of (x1/2 +x2/3)9?",
        answer: "84"
    },
    {
        problem: "Determine the sum of the squares of the x-coordinates of the intersection points of y = 2018 x and y = 2018 − x2.",
        answer: "4036"
    },
    {
        problem: "A semi-circle ωAC circumscribes 3 − 4 − 5 triangle ABC. A semi-circle ωBC with diameter BC and another semi-circle ωAB with diameter AB are constructed outside the triangle. What is the shaded area inside ωBC and ωAB but outside ωAC?",
        answer: "(D) 6"
    },
    {
        problem: "If f(a + b) = f(a)f(b) for positive integers a and b and f(1) = √-1 what the value of f(2015)?",
        answer: "(B) -√-1"
    },
    {
        problem: "In △ABC, AB = AC, M and N lie on BC such that AM and AN trisect ∠BAC with M lying closer to B. If BM = 3·MN and AM = 8, what is the length of AB?",
        answer: "24"
    },
    {
        problem: "If f(x) = mx+b for m < 0 and f(x) = 4f−1(x)+3, what is the sum m+b?",
        answer: "-5"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let S be the set of all pairs (x, y) of positive integers such that 9x2 − 4y2 =540. Find the sum of all coordinates in the set S.",
        answer: "48"
    },
    {
        problem: "Two angles of a triangle are x+28 and 4x+5. If all the angles are integers, what is the measure of the smallest possible angle of this triangle?",
        answer: "1"
    },
    {
        problem: "A urn has an equal number of white marbles and black marbles in it. You take two marbles randomly from the urn and see that they are the same color. Now you take two more marbles randomly from the urn and the probability that the second pair of marbles match in color (not necessarily the same color as the first pair) is 7 15. What is the smallest possible number of marbles in the urn originally?",
        answer: "8"
    },
    {
        problem: "A regular hexagon is centered at the origin in the complex plane. If one vertex is at 2 + 4√2i, the area of the hexagon can be written as a√b where the prime factorization of b has no square. Find a + b.",
        answer: "57"
    },
    {
        problem: "If log2 x + logx 4 = 3 what is the sum of all values of x?",
        answer: "6"
    },
    {
        problem: "What is the smallest positive integer that has half as many factors as 224?",
        answer: "12"
    },
    {
        problem: "Each straight line segment in the accompanying figure is 1 inch long and the entire figure is a simple closed loop. The whole figure has a total perimeter of 186 inches. What is the total area of the figure in square inches?",
        answer: "92"
    },
    {
        problem: "Solve for x: 9 −1−5x 9 −5−3x = 9−4x−2",
        answer: "-3"
    },
    {
        problem: "For 0 < θ < 25◦, if cos θ = cos(14θ), what is the value of θ?",
        answer: "24"
    },
    {
        problem: "When a volcano erupts, fine particles of ash are ejected miles into the sky. As they fall, they coalesce into spheres of pumice. The volume the sphere attains when it reaches the ground is directly proportional to the height the ash reaches. If from a height of 8 miles, the volume attained is 3π cubic centimeters, then if the sphere formed from an attained height of 12 miles has a radius, in simplest terms, of a b , what is a + b?",
        answer: "5"
    },
    {
        problem: "From the set {1, 2, 3, 4, 5}, how many subsets do not have a pair of elements which differ by 1? (For example, the subset {1, 3, 5} has no pairs which differ by 1, but the subset {1, 2, 5} does have a pair which differs by 1.)",
        answer: "13"
    },
    {
        problem: "Given that u is 75% of the size of w, w is 50% larger than z and x is 25% smaller than z, by what percent is u larger than x?",
        answer: "50"
    },
    {
        problem: "If the graphs of y = x2 −ax+b and y = x2 −bx+a intersect in exactly one point, what is the x-coordinate of that point?",
        answer: "-1"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let a, b, and c be relatively prime integers with a > 0. If the roots of ax2 + bx + c = 0 are −2 3 and 1 5, what is the value of a + b + c?",
        answer: "20"
    },
    {
        problem: "Determine the sum: 1 − 2 − 3 − 4 + 5 − 6 − 7 − 8 + 9 − 10 − 11 − 12 + 13 − · · · − 2020.",
        answer: "-1022120"
    },
    {
        problem: "The vertices of a square are (7, 12), (3, 6), (9, 2) and (13, 8). The line through (2, −3) divides the square into two parts of equal area. The line’s equation can be written as Ax + By + C = 0 where A, B and C are relatively prime integers with A > 0. What is A + B + C?",
        answer: "-17"
    },
    {
        problem: "One urn contain 3 white balls and 5 black balls. A second urn contains 5 white balls and 4 black balls. From each urn two balls are selected at random without replacement. The probability of selecting 4 white balls can be written in simplest form as a b. What is a + b?",
        answer: "173"
    },
    {
        problem: "The isosceles 4ABC has a base of AB = 1 and side lengths of AC = BC = 2. Another isosceles 4DEF is inscribed in 4ABC with D on AC, E on BC, and F on AB such that AD = BE = 1. The area of 4DEF can be written in simplest form as √a b . What is a + b?",
        answer: "31"
    },
    {
        problem: "Don has a an unusually shaped cabin in the woods, with four rectangular rooms, according the plan shown in the figure. All dimensions of the rooms are an integer number of meters. Rooms ABCD and CEFD share a common side CD and rooms GHIJ and IJKL share common side IJ. Some of the outside dimensions are shown in the figure, AB = 7 meters, AG = 4 meters, FK = 3 meters and GH = 6 meters. The area of three of the rooms in square meters is also shown: the area of ABCD is 35, the area of DCEF is 42 and the area of GHIJ is 36. What is the area of the shaded rectangle, IJKL, in square meters?",
        answer: "24"
    },
    {
        problem: "How many 6-digit numbers contain the digit-trio 123 at least once?",
        answer: "3699"
    },
    {
        problem: "Shown is a graph of x2 64 + y2 4 = 1. If AB = BC = CD = DE, what is 4 times the length of AB?",
        answer: "17"
    },
    {
        problem: "A radius of a circle is drawn. A second radius is drawn 17◦ in a clockwise direction from the first. A third radius is then drawn 17◦ in a clockwise direction from the second. This process continues until 30 radii have been drawn. What is the smallest possible angle between two of the radii?",
        answer: "3"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let N = 0.b0b0 and M = 0.0b0b where b is an integer from 1 to 9 inclusive and 0.b0b0 indicates the repeating decimal 0.b0b0b0 . . .. If N − M N + M = 9 11, compute the sum of all possible values of b.",
        answer: "45"
    },
    {
        problem: "9 cards that are face down have been put at random into a pile of 5 cards and a pile of 4. It is known that there are 6 red cards and 3 black cards. The probability that at least one pile contains only red cards is m n where m and n are relatively prime. What is m + n?",
        answer: "7"
    },
    {
        problem: "How many solutions in integers x and y does the equation x3 + 2y2 = xy2 + 8 have?",
        answer: "(E) More than four"
    },
    {
        problem: "Equilateral 4DEF is inscribed in equilateral 4ABC with DF ⊥ AB and AD = 2. What is the ratio of the area of 4ABC to the area of 4DEF?",
        answer: "3"
    },
    {
        problem: "How many real roots (counting multiplicities) does the polynomial x4 + 2x3 + 2x2 + 2x + 1 have?",
        answer: "2"
    },
    {
        problem: "Consider the accompanying figure. Points D, A, B lie on a straight line. Circles with centers at A, B, and C have radius 1 and are mutually tangent. Circles with centers A, D, and E have radius 1 and are also mutually tangent. Rectangle HIJK is circumscribed about the 5 circles so that HI is tangent to circles D and C, IJ is tangent to circles C and B, JK is tangent to circles B and E, and KH is tangent to circles E and D. The area of HIJK can be written in simplest form as a + b√c where the prime factorization of c contains no squares. Whatis a + b + c?",
        answer: "19"
    },
    {
        problem: "The radius of the largest circle that can be inscribed in a 120◦sector of a larger circle with radius 1 can be written in simplest form a√b−c, where simplest form means the prime factorization of b has no squares. What is a + b + c?",
        answer: "8"
    },
    {
        problem: "Rhombus ABCD with side length 3 is separated from congruent rhombus EF GH by parallelogram BEHC. Segment AG intersects BC at L. The length BL = 1. What is BE?",
        answer: "3"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let ABCDEFGH be a regular octagon of side length 2. Let X be the intersection of BH with AG and Y be the intersection of BH with AC. The square of the length of segment XY, that is, XY2 can be written in simplest form as a − b√c. What is a + b + c?",
        answer: "14"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let n be an integer with n > 2. What is the remainder when the product n(n + 2)(n + 3) is divided by n − 2?",
        answer: "40"
    },
    {
        problem: "In 4ABC, ∠ABC = 90◦, AB = 6 BC = 16, BE ⊥ AD and D is the midpoint of BC. The length of BE can be written in simplest form as m n. What is m + n?",
        answer: "281"
    },
    {
        problem: "A square 2017 by 2017 is divided into unit squares. Starting from the lower left corner, Al walks to the upper right corner by stepping on the squares that lie on the diagonal. Starting from the same lower left corner, Bob steps 3 squares to the right, then 4 squares up, then 2 squares up, followed by 3 squares to the right. He continues that procedure until he arrives at the upper right corner. If Al steps on m squares and Bob steps on n squares, what is the ratio of n to m? Note: the lower left hand corner that they start on is not counted as a step.",
        answer: "2"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let the perimeter of a rectangle be 4k and x be the length of a short side of the rectangle. For how many integer values of x is the area numerically less than the perimeter for all values of k?",
        answer: "2"
    },
    {
        problem: "Let bac be the greatest integer less than or equal to a. Let dae be the least integer greater than or equal to a. The area enclosed by the system below equals m n in simplest form. What is m + n? x ≥ 0, y ≥ 0 bxc + dye ≤ 5 x + y ≥ 5",
        answer: "7"
    },
    {
        problem: "A square MNOP is inscribed in a regular octagon ABCDEFGH of side length 1 with the vertices of the square at the midpoints of AB, CD, EF and GH. The side length of the square can be expressed as a +√bc where the prime factorization of b contains no squares. What isa + b + c?",
        answer: "5"
    },
    {
        problem: "Shown in the figure is an array of numbers in which, except for the elements at the two ends of a row, an element in a row is the sum oft he two elements in the preceding row that are just above it. What is the sum of all the elements in the first 10 rows?",
        answer: "3069"
    },
    {
        problem: "What is the largest value of t such that 3x2 − 2x + t = 0 has real solutions?",
        answer: "1/3"
    },
    {
        problem: "In 4ABC, BC = 9, D is chosen on BC such that BD = 6, and E is chosen on AC such that DE k AB. If the area of 4ADE = 8, determine the area of 4ABC.",
        answer: "36"
    },
]